Laura Witherspoon

Front-end engineer, technical lead, and aspiring software engineer with 5 years of experience in the tech field communicating effectively with developers, business stakeholders, project managers, and end-users. Always driven to learn the latest trends and best practices to deliver well-performing, modern web applications that users love.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Agile/Scrum methodology NPM, Grunt Java

Requirements gathering/analysis AngularJS PHP (WordPress templating)

Git version control with GitHub JavaScript, JSON, and jQuery SQL

RESTful APIs and AJAX HTML & CSS, (Sass and Less) WordPress, Drupal, SharePoint

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NRECA, Sr. Front-End Developer and Technical Lead

Nov 2014 to Present

Lead four-person development team to bring web project visions to reality and ensure they meet expectations by translating business goals into prioritized technical requirements needed for successful project completion.

- Define and manage development tasks and serve as interface between project manager and developers
- Mentor junior developers and guide architecturally important technical decisions
- Communicate technical issues and decisions in business terms to project sponsors
- Coordinate with QA testers to design and build testable features

Project: Cooperative.com Redesign (April 2017 - Feb 2018)

- Delivered 12-month project on schedule, providing highly customized SharePoint interface that enables
 Communications team to self-manage visually appealing, compelling content
- New site increased weekly views by ~20,000 and decreased bounce rate by ~50%
- Personally architected and built repeatable content engine using JSOM that reads and writes SharePoint data via API, allowing editors to easily update list data without leaving the page edit screen

Project: Rural Electric Safety Achievement Program Web Application (Oct 2016 - May 2017)

- Increased user engagement with angular web application by streamlining organization of form required data required by translating focus-group feedback into technical requirements for development team
- Reduced volume of help calls from users to program administrators by designing and implementing clear design patterns throughout the web application

Project: Cooperative.com Website Redesign (Jan 2015 - Mar 2016)

- Successfully transitioned private member website from SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2013, resulting in noted decrease in negative user feedback, freeing up team resources to focus on other initiatives
- Eliminated manual update process for event data by programmatically retrieving and displaying data in realtime via API, reducing time spent creating and maintaining event webpages

The Knowland Group, Marketing Coordinator

Oct 2013 to Nov 2014

Managed all online strategies to increase web application and website traffic, lead generation, and user engagement.

- Participated in agile planning sessions to help identify and prioritize enhancements needed in web application
- Shortened web content update cycle from several weeks to a couple hours by designing and coding custom
 Drupal interface, migrating static website content and regression testing website

Acumatica, Website Manager and Marketing Assistant

Feb 2013 to Oct 2013

Responsible for all website changes, increasing web conversion rates, and weekly reporting on website performance metrics for the marketing department.

EDUCATION

Northern Virginia Community College Java Programming (CSC 201) Discrete Mathematics (Math 286) George Mason University
M.A. in Global Affairs, May 2014
Global Economics & Development

James Madison University
B.A. in Modern Foreign Languages,
May 2012, French and Russian